# Crystal Carrillo

Technical Professional - cryskayecarr@gmail.com - 539-210-6478

CKCarr.dev • https://github.com/CKCarr • https://www.linkedin.com/in/crystal-carrillo/

## PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Highly motivated and detail-oriented software developer, Professional with diverse skill set founded with excellent communication, empathy, and resourcefulness. Over a decade of experience in healthcare, customer service, operations. Honed technical skills and strong passion for creating solutions through problem solving and team collaboration.

## **EDUCATION**

Atlas School Tulsa - Tulsa. Ok

Diploma in Computer Science and Full Stack Web Development January 2023 - August 2024

- Completing 20-month immersive, hands-on, project-based curriculum
- Fundamentals of computer science and web development
- Student of the Month February 2024

## **EXPERIENCE**

## Pro Care Innovations - Owasso, Ok

Telehealth Care Team Coordinator / Medical Assistant

August 2022 - November 2022

- Updated patient charts and maintained secure, up-to-date information in medical software.
- Ensured the confidentiality and security of patient information in compliance with healthcare regulations.
- Proficient in using medical software and managing tasks via computer and email to streamline communication and record-keeping.

## Brookdale Senio Living - Weatherford, Ok

Business Office Manager,

Certified Nurse Assistant / Advanced Certified Medication Aide.

July 2014 - March 2018

- Updated and organized employee and resident files.
- Audited Kronos time clock and handled employee onboarding.
- Took on multiple roles as needed, ensuring efficient operations and problem-solving.

## **SKILLS & STRENGTHS**

Healthcare | Customer Service | Janitorial / Housekeeping | Money-handling | Business Office Management | Filing | Organization | Quality Assurance | Project management | Independent as well as Team Collaborator Oriented | Excellent written and verbal communication | Computer skills | Positive and Professional attitude | Motivated to Learn

## **VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE**

Techlahoma - Tulsa Web Devs - Co-Organizer - 2024

## Crystal Carrillo

Technical Professional - cryskayecarr@gmail.com - 539-210-6478

CKCarr.dev • https://github.com/CKCarr • https://www.linkedin.com/in/crystal-carrillo/

## **PROJECTS**

#### **PRINTF** – Re-created printf function in C

- Prints formatted strings to standard output (terminal).
- Included a flowchart (draw.io) and a custom man-page in the README.

## SIMPLE SHELL - Developed a simple UNIX command interpreter in C.

Executes bash commands input by the user via the command line interface (CLI).

## Mock AIRBNB - Built an AirBnB clone in Python over multiple project versions.

- Dual storage system using JSON and MySQL.
- Front End: HTML, CSS, JavaScript | Back End: Python, Flask.
- Utilized jQuery for dynamic updates and AJAX calls to the back end.

## Museum of Imagination - Themed Hack Sprint Partner Project w/ Three.js

- Created two 3D galleries using Three.js, including design, menus, audio, and movement.
- Contributed to CSS animations on the homepage (rolling clouds, blinking windows).

## SmilingSchool - Designer File to Website

Built an interactive, responsive website from a Figma design using JavaScript.

#### A Way Home - Capstone Project

Developed a lost and found pet application using Next.js, React, and Tailwind CSS.

### Cinema Guru – Create React Application

- Built a React front-end application connecting to a movie API
- Features include Login, Favorites, and "Watch Later" functionality

## **Technical Skills**

Programming Languages:

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, TypeScript, C, Python

Web Technologies & Frameworks:

React, Tailwind, ¡Query, Node.js, UI/UX, Figma

❖ Databases & APIs:

MySQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, JSON, APIs

**❖** Tools & Version Control:

Git/GitHub, Docker, Command Line Interface (CLI), Microsoft 365, Agile

Operating Systems:

Linux, Windows